Rose Gaban Frontend Developer

™ rosegaban@gmail.com

rgaban.github.io/ github.com/rgaban/

in linkedin.com/in/rosegaban/

I'm a self-taught Frontend Developer with a background on customer advocacy. I'm passionate about problem solving and optimizing for long-term fitting solutions, and care deeply about customer experience through careful requirements gathering and well-thought-out designs.

Professional Experience

Customer Success Manager, Import.io

Oct 2019 - Jul 2020 | Saratoga, CA

A trusted technical advisor to customers and collaborated internally to drive business value, customer success and growth.

- Actively engaged with key stakeholders, designed and executed account plans through cadence meetings and quarterly business reviews, and proactively identified opportunities for expansion.
- Worked closely with customers and the Support Team to manage expectations and ensured SLAs were met.
- Performed risk assessments and worked with internal teams to mitigate risks.
- Collaborated with the Product & Engineering team to drive customer requests, influencing product roadmap.

Sales Engineer, Import.io

Nov 2018 – Oct 2019 | Saratoga, CA

Worked with potential and existing customers to enable their use case throughout the sales cycle.

- Scoped, designed, and demonstrated Import.io business value for customer use cases through proof of concepts.
- Responsible for technical pre-sales activities including presentations and demos, to both technical and non-technical audiences.

Customer Success Engineer, Import.io

Oct 2017 - Nov 2018 | Saratoga, CA

Responsible for laying a framework for the Success Team to ensure scalability to support the company's growth by implementing support processes and best practices from the ground up.

- Understood client's technical requirements and offered product expertise through onboarding, working sessions, and providing proactive support through account health checks.
- Designed and established Import.io Knowledge Base to help the client become self-sufficient.
- Implemented field-engineered solutions to unblock customers and report back to Product & Engineering proposing such solutions be incorporated into core product offering.

📛 Projects

DevKeep, An application geared for developers, enabling them to take notes while attaching code snippets.

- Built with React & custom CSS for the frontend, and Supabase.io which utilizes PostgreSQL database for the backend.
- Implemented authentication to secure user notes, layering security on both the frontend and backend.
- Auto-save functionality with a notification system with any add/edit/delete.
- Supports Optimistic UI Rendering for an improved & snappier user experience.

PawPrint, A single page application that tracks pet owners and their pet's activities, including feeding time, walks, etc.

- Built with React & custom CSS for the frontend, and Firebase for the backend.
- Applied layered authentication to both the frontend and backend to keep information secure.

NASA Astronomy Picture of the Day, An application that pulls space & science related images through NASA's API.

- Built with React & custom CSS for the frontend.
- Integrated with NASA's API to obtain images/videos & descriptions with the ability to save favorites using local storage.

🕅 Languages, Libraries & Frameworks

• HTML5

• CSS₃

• JavaScript

• React

NextIS

• Redux

• SQL

• Bootstrap

Education